<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Science | Hasan Kurban, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/material-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/material-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Material Science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code with  and  Blogdown
© Hasan Kurban, 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.hasankurban.com/images/icon_hu20e5e5b4446f9fea2c18d55ef2678e39_24096_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Material Science</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/material-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Type Prediction with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/atomtypeprediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/atomtypeprediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to determine machine learning  (ML) algorithms that can learn nanoparticles best. The mathematical structural features of the ML algorithm which is most compatible with such data  can help material scientist estimate behavior, structural and electronic properties of nano particles in different temperatures and phases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Data Science over Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/correlation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this work, we analyse the correlations between structural and electronic properties of anatase, brookite and rutile phases TiO2 nanoparticles (NPs) using data science techniques. For this purpose, we use the geometries of three phases TiO2 NPs under heat treatment obtained from molecular dynamics (MD) simulations in the frame of DFTB+ code. We investigate the relationships among electronic properties of TiO2 and order parameter R or segregation phenomena &amp;amp; nearest number contacts n. In this architecture, the correlations among HOMO, LUMO, Energy gap (Eg), Fermi energy (Ef), R and n have been analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Analysis of  TiO2 Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, we perform a theoretical investigation using the density functional tight binding (DFTB) approach for the structural analysis and electronic structure of anatase, brookite and rutile phase TiO2 nanoparticles (NPs). Our results show that the number of Ti-O bonds is more than that of O-O while the number of Ti-Ti bonds are the less. Thus, large amount of O atoms prefers to connect to Ti atoms. The increase in the temperature of the NPs contributes to an increase in the interaction of Ti–O bonding, but a decrease in the O-O bonding. The segregation of Ti and O atoms shows that Ti atoms tend to co-locate at the center, while O atoms tend to reside on the surface. Increasing temperature causes decrease of the bandgap from 3.59 to 2.62 eV for brookite phase, which is much more energetically favorable compared to bulk while it could increase the bandgap from 3.15 to 3.61 eV for anatase phase. For three phase TiO2 NPs, LUMO and Fermi levels decrease. The HOMO level of anatase phase NP decrease, but it increases for brookite and rutile phase TiO2 nanoparticles. Herein, an increase in the temperature contributes to the stabilization of anatase phase TiO2 NP due to decrease in the HOMO energies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/m1-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/m1-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to conduct structural analysis, we also developed programs in R language  to analyze the number of bonds, segregation phenomena, and RDF. We perform a theoretical investigation using the density functional tight binding (DFTB) approach for the structural analysis and electronic structure of copper hydride (CuH) metallic nanoparticles (NPs) of different size (from 204 to 2418 atoms). By increasing the size of CuH NPs, the number of bonds, segregation phenomena and radial distribution function (RDF) of binary Cu-Cu, Cu-H and H-H interactions are investigated using new algorithms. The results reveal that the number of bonds Cu-Cu is larger than that of Cu-H while H2 bonds are the smallest. Thus, the ability of Cu atoms to absorb large amounts of H is more than H2. The increase in the size of the NPs contributes to the stabilization because of the enhanced strength of H–H bonding. The segregation of Cu and H atoms show that Cu atoms tend to co-locate at the center, while H atoms tend to reside on the surface. From the density of state (DOS) analysis, CuH NPs shows a metallic character which is compatible with experimental data. HOMO and Fermi levels decrease from -3.555 to -3.443 eV and from -3.510 to -3.441 eV. Herein, an increase in the size contributes to the stabilization of CuH NP due to decrease in the HOMO energies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
