<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial intelligence | Hasan Kurban, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Artificial intelligence</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Code with  and  Blogdown
© Hasan Kurban, 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.hasankurban.com/images/icon_hu20e5e5b4446f9fea2c18d55ef2678e39_24096_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/tag/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom Type Prediction with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/atomtypeprediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/atomtypeprediction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to determine machine learning  (ML) algorithms that can learn nanoparticles best. The mathematical structural features of the ML algorithm which is most compatible with such data  can help material scientist estimate behavior, structural and electronic properties of nano particles in different temperatures and phases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Based Hospital Appointment System</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/healthproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/healthproject/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fact that some of the symptoms are related to many medical treatment areas causes patients to have difficulty in making an appointment for treatment.  In this project, we design a data-driven system to find solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Big Data</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/em-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/em-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Existing data mining techniques, more particularly iterative learning algorithms, become overwhelmed with big data. While parallelism is an obvious and, usually, necessary strategy, we observe that both (1) continually
revisiting data and (2) visiting all data are two of the most prominent problems especially for iterative, unsupervised algorithms like Expectation Maximization algorithm for clustering (EM-T). Our strategy is to embed EM-T into a non-linear hierarchical data structure (heap) that allows us to (1) separate data that needs to be revisited from data that does not and (2) narrow the iteration toward the data that is more difficult to cluster. We call this extended EM-T, EM*. We show our EM* algorithm outperform EM-T algorithm over large real world and synthetic data sets. We lastly conclude with some theoretic underpinnings that explain why EM* is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/rf-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.hasankurban.com/project/rf-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Random Forests have been used as effective ensemble models for classification. We present in this paper a new type of Random Forests (RFs) called Red(uced)-RF that adopts a new dynamic data reduction principle and a new voting mechanism called Priority Vote Weighting (PV) which improve accuracy, execution time and AUC values compared to Breiman’s RF. Red-RF also shows that the strength of a random forest can increase without noticeably increasing correlation between the trees. We then compare performance of Red-RF and Breiman’s RF in 8 experiments that involve classification problems with datasets of different sizes. Finally, we conduct two additional experiments that involve considerably larger datasets with one million points in each.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
